Guide to the Hans Bethe papers, ca. 1931-1995
Bethe, Hans papers,
- Series IV. Subject Files
  - Arms Control
    - Arms Control, testimony to Senate Committee on Foreign Relations (1982) (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - Arms Control, unpublished ms. submitted to Nation (1982) (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - Arms Control, newspaper clippings and draft of response by Bethe (1982) (Box 77, Folder 16)
    - Catholic Church on Peace (1982) (Box 77, Folder 17)
    - Nuclear Arms - Noel Gayler speech (1983) (Box 77, Folder 18)
    - Deterrence - papers by N. Lebow, D. Ball (1984) (Box 77, Folder 19)
    - "The Military Role of Nuclear Weapons: Perceptions and Misperceptions," R. McNamara, Foreign Affairs (1983) (Box 77, Folder 20)
    - Draft: "Constraints on Fissionable Materials for Weapons - a revival of old proposals," W.K.H. Panofsky (1982) (Box 77, Folder 21)
    - Seismic Detection, SIPRI (Stockholm International Peace Research Institute)(1969) (Box 77, Folder 22)
    - European Nuclear Weapons (Box 77, Folder 23)
    - Arms Control Compliance (Box 77, Folder 24)
    - Gottfried Study (Box 77, Folder 25)
    - Pugwash on Chemical War (Box 77, Folder 26)
    - Pierre Noyes - Debunking a fantasy of use of nuclear weapon in San Francisco Bay (1981-82) (Box 77, Folder 27)
    - Arms Control - Rathjens Testimony, Yankelowitch, Center Defense Info. (Box 77, Folder 28)
    - T. Postol, articles on Nuclear War (Box 77, Folder 29)
    - Soviet Military Power (1981); NATO vs. Warsw Pact (Box 77, Folder 32)
    - Soviet Defense Trends (1983) (Box 77, Folder 33)
    - Letter Supporting Soviet Dissidents (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - "Deterrence and Coercion in Soviet Policy," D.K. Simes International Security (1980-81) (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - "Entering the Nuclear Arms Race: The Soviet Decision to Build the Atomic Bomb, 1939-45," D. Holloway (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - Peter Stein lecture: "War and Justice: Is it ever right to kill?" (1983) (Box 77, Folder 37)
    - United Campuses to Prevent Nuclear War (UCAM) Congressional Canvas (1982) (Box 77, Folder 38)
    - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists articles (some by Bethe)(1981-84) (Box 77, Folder 39)
    - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists sponsors (1981) (Box 77, Folder 40)
    - "The Technological Imperative," by Bethe Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists (1985) (Box 77, Folder 41)
    - Meeting, Cornell and Frankfurt Peace Studies (1985) (Box 77, Folder 42)
    - Pugwash, etc. (1982-83) (Box 77, Folder 43)
    - Trialogue, Security and Disarmament (1982) (Box 77, Folder 44)
    - The Five Continent Peace Imitative: Parliamentarians for World Order; Pontifical Academy (1985) (Box 77, Folder 45)
    - Report of the Theater Nuclear Forces Sub-Panel Congressional Study Group on New Directions in National Security and Arms Control (1982) (Box 77, Folder 46)
    - Senate Foreign Relations Committee (1982), Statements by Adm. N. Gayler, R.C. Molander (Box 77, Folder 47)
    - UCLA Conference on Security and Arms Control (includes transcript of talk by Bethe)(1982) (Box 77, Folder 48)
    - Commemoration of 40th anniversary of first nuclear chain reaction, Chicago (1982) (Box 77, Folder 49)
    - Arms, Miscellaneous (Box 77, Folder 50)
    - Correspondence/interview questions re: arms race (Box 77, Folder 51)
    - S. Drell (1982-83) (Box 77, Folder 52)
    - Rathjens, Panofsky, Gerald Johnson, George Ball (1982-83) (Box 77, Folder 53)
    - V.F. Weisskopf (1981-84) (Box 77, Folder 54)
    - J. Bokaer (1984) (Box 77, Folder 55)
    - Nuclear Times (1983) (Box 77, Folder 56)
    - Reactions to July 16, Congressional hearing (1985) (Box 77, Folder 59)
    - "The Arms Race," Bethe (1985) (Box 77, Folder 60)
    - State Department on relations with Soviet Union (1982-86) (Box 77, Folder 62-63)
    - Department of Defense and State Department (1982-85) (Box 77, Folder 63)
    - Newspaper clippings on Bethe's activities re: arms race (1984) (Box 77, Folder 65)
    - Testimony to House Committee on Arms Control (1985) (Box 77, Folder 66)
    - Papers by Bethe (1950-62) (Box 77, Folder 67)
    - McCarthyism (1954) (Box 77, Folder 68)
    - Shepley Blair book on H-bomb (1954) (Box 77, Folder 69-70)
    - Los Alamos 40 year commemoration (1983) (Box 77, Folder 71)
    - Nuclear Weapons: Pro and Con Arms Control (Box 82, Folder 19)
    - Council for Arms Control (British) (Box 82, Folder 20)
    - Arms Control Miscellaneous (Box 82, Folder 21)
    - History of Arms Control (Box 82, Folder 22)
    - European Security, No First Use (1982) (Box 82, Folder 23-24)
    - Hoopes, Soviet Embassy, NPQ interview (1986-87) (Box 82, Folder 48)
    - Joan Bokaer (1985) (Box 82, Folder 49)
    - Articles by Weiskopf, George Ball, Jane sharp, Japanese Mathematicians' Petition (Box 82, Folder 50)
    - Bethe Statements re: Arms Control (1982) (Box 85, Folder 31)
    - Scientific American article (1984) (Box 86, Folder 27-28)
    - National Teach-in on Nuclear War - November 11, 1981 (Box 93, Folder 26)
    - Arms Control - Talk and Background - Cambridge (1988) (Box 97, Folder 8)
    - Arms Control - articles, clippings (1981-83) (Box 99, Folder 24-26)
    - Union of Concerned Scientists (UCS)
      - UCS Commemoration of July 16 (Trinity test, first nuclear explosion; includes address by Bethe) (1985) (Box 77, Folder 57)
      - Preparations for UCS Commemoration of July 16, pamphlet, Morrison talk (Box 77, Folder 58)
      - UCS Confidential Memoranda (1984) (Box 77, Folder 64)
      - UCS Workshop on "Western Nuclear Policy and the New Geopolitical Context," Arlie House, VA, June 13-16, 1991 (Box 95, Folder 9-12)
      - UCS (1982-83) (Box 97, Folder 43)
      - UCS - various papers (1982-85) (Box 97, Folder 44)
      - UCS (1982-89) (Box 97, Folder 45)
      - UCS (1983-90) (Box 97, Folder 46)
      - UCS (1986) (Box 97, Folder 47)
      - UCS - Washington (1986) (Box 97, Folder 48)
  - Atomic Power Development Associates, Inc. (APDA)
    - APDA: Bethe-Tait Accident (Box 66, Folder 22-23)
    - APDA: General Information (Box 66, Folder 24)
    - APDA: PRDC I (Box 66, Folder 25)
    - APDA: PRDC II Own Testimony, Comments, Calculations, Important Information (Box 66, Folder 26)
    - APDA: PRDC III (Box 66, Folder 27-28)
    - APDA: Doppler Effect (Box 66, Folder 29)
    - APDA: Kinetics (Box 66, Folder 30)
    - APDA: Lawsuit I (Box 66, Folder 31-32)
    - APDA: Lawsuit II (Box 66, Folder 33-34)
    - APDA: Lawsuit III (Box 66, Folder 35)
    - Bethe-Tait Accident (Box 67, Folder 35)
  - Atomic Energy Commission (AEC)
    - Correspondence related to AEC (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - AEC Documents Inventory (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with Dr. C. Marshall, AEC (Box 67, Folder 5-7)
    - AEC Miscellaneous (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - AEC: Lawrence Radiation Lab (Box 67, Folder 26)
  - Atomic Power Development Association (APDA)
    - APDA (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - APDA (Box 67, Folder 11-12)
  - AVCO-Everett Research Laboratory
    - AVCO re: HIPAC (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - AVCO-Wilmington Ablation (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - AVCO-Wilmington: AICBM (Calculations) (Box 67, Folder 15)
    - AVCO-Wilmington: EM Scatter from Wake (1962-63) (Box 67, Folder 16-17)
    - AVCO: Suppression of Ionization in Wake (Box 67, Folder 18-19)
    - AVCO: Papers and Reprints (Box 67, Folder 20)
    - AVCO: ABM and Preparation (Box 67, Folder 21)
    - AVCO: Ablation (Box 67, Folder 22)
    - Papers/Graphs: AVCO (Box 67, Folder 23)
    - AVCO: Missile Systems (Box 67, Folder 24)
    - Avco Isotopes, Lawsuit in Israel (Box 81, Folder 23)
    - Avco (1983-84) (Box 87, Folder 37)
  - Fulbright Fellowship, 1955-56
    - Correspondence (1955-56) (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Recommendations (1955-56) (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Fulbright Fellowship (1955-56) (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - University Students (1955-56) (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence re: lectures, etc. (1955-56) (Box 83, Folder 6-8)
    - Invitations refused (1955-56) (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - U.S.-U.K. Reactor Conference (1955-56) (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence (1955-56) (Box 83, Folder 10a)
  - Nuclear Energy
    - Probability of Accident in Nuclear Plant, Bethe's Testimony to California Legislature (1975); "The Energy Crisis and Nuclear Contributions to its Solution" (1974) (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Energy Information (1976-81) (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - International Scientific Forum on Energy, Meting at Fort Lauderdale (1984) (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Nuclear Power, Miscellaneous (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Nuclear Safety, Doderlein, others (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Nuclear Safety, Hannum et al. (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Nuclear Power, Standardization (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - APS (American Physical Society) Safety Study, Correspondence (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - Safeguards (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - British Report on Sizewell B (Box 81, Folder 12)
    - Risk Assessment, Bodansky (Box 81, Folder 13)
    - LMFBR (liquid-metal cooled fast breeder reactors) Risk Assessment, Bell et al. (Box 81, Folder 14)
    - Atomic Industrial Forum (Box 81, Folder 15)
    - Atomic Industrial Forum - Info (Box 81, Folder 16)
    - Americans for Energy Independence (1980-85) (Box 81, Folder 17)
    - Americans for Energy Independence (1984-87) (Box 81, Folder 18)
    - Scientists and Engineers for Secure Energy (SE2)(1979-84) (Box 81, Folder 19-20)
    - Scientists and Engineers for Secure Energy (SE2)(1985-88) (Box 81, Folder 21)
    - Amicus Brief to Supreme Court re: 3-Mile Island (Box 81, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence with Jeremy Bernstein (Box 81, Folder 24)
    - Non-nuclear Energy, Livermore, February (1979) (Box 81, Folder 25)
    - Energy Lectures (1976-79) (Box 81, Folder 26)
    - Reactor Lectures (ca. 1976) (Box 81, Folder 27)
    - Energy Talks (1977-78) (Box 81, Folder 28)
    - Energy Lectures; University of Washington, Texas (1976-77) (Box 81, Folder 29)
    - Energy Revisited (1979) (Box 81, Folder 30)
    - Corson Committee on Solar Power from Satellite (Box 81, Folder 31)
    - Talk, Cornell - Sept. 8 1980 (Box 81, Folder 32)
    - Energy Independence is Possible (ca. 1981) (Box 81, Folder 33)
    - Energy Talks (1981-82) (Box 81, Folder 34)
    - Testimony to Committee on Energy Research and Production (Box 81, Folder 35)
    - Comments by others on Energy (ca. 1980) (Box 81, Folder 36)
    - Source Term in Reactor Accident, Levenson and Rahn (Box 81, Folder 37)
    - Solar Power for Heating, Los Alamos (1976) (Box 81, Folder 38)
    - Energy Talks: Brazil, Cal Tech, Santa Barbara, Lovins (1980) (Box 81, Folder 39)
    - Energy Talks (1979) (Box 81, Folder 40)
    - Fusion Hybrid - Physics Today; also Argonne Citizen, 1978 (Box 81, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence re: book on Nuclear Power, edited by Kaku (Box 81, Folder 42)
    - Shielding against Gamma Rays and Neutrons (1947) (Box 81, Folder 43)
    - Biological Effects of Ionizing Radiation (Box 81, Folder 44)
    - Fusion, General (Box 81, Folder 45)
    - Accelerator Breeder (Box 81, Folder 46)
    - Hybrid, Inertial Fusion (Box 81, Folder 47)
    - Economics of Nuclear Power (Box 81, Folder 48)
    - Energy required to build nuclear reactors (Box 81, Folder 49)
    - Solar Energy (Box 81, Folder 50-52)
    - Remarks at Nobel Prize including talk to Swedish Atomic Energy (Box 81, Folder 53)
    - Energy: General Information (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Energy Papers by Others (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Project Independence: articles on coal, co-generation (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Scientists and Engineers for Secure Energy (SE2)(1984) (Box 90, Folder 15)
    - Henry Linden on natural gas (1979) (Box 93, Folder 24)
    - Controls on Atomic Energy
      - UN Atomic Energy Commission (1947) (Box 82, Folder 4-5)
      - International Control of Atomic Energy (Box 82, Folder 6)
      - Emergency Committee of Atomic Scientists (1946-48) (Box 82, Folder 7)
      - Scientists' Movement (1945-69) (Box 82, Folder 8)
      - Early Issues of Bulletin of Atomic Scientists (Box 82, Folder 9)
      - Federation of American Scientists, and local branches; Sakharov paper (Box 82, Folder 10)
  - Nuclear Testing/Test Ban
    - Calculations on Detection of Weapons Tests at High Altitude (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Test Ban: Bethe article in Atlantic Monthly (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Detection of Tests - Calculations on Seismic Waves (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - Small Stations - Roberts - Other Techniques to Improve Detection (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Geneva Test Negotiations: Official Reports I and II (Box 64, Folder 13-14)
    - Test Ban: Tech Statements (Romney, et al) (Box 64, Folder 15)
    - Test Ban: Seismic Materials I and II (1959) (Box 64, Folder 16-17)
    - Atomic Weapons Test Ban: Private Articles (Box 64, Folder 18)
    - Test Ban: Boyd Press Statements, etc. (Box 64, Folder 19)
    - Geneva Conference (December 1959); Photos of Summer "Conference of Experts" (1958) (Box 64, Folder 20)
    - Congressional Hearings on Test Ban: Testimony (April 1960) (Box 64, Folder 21)
    - Test Ban: Lecture Notes, Manuscript, Shelter, Arms Control (Box 64, Folder 22)
    - Test Ban: Correspondence, talks (outlines), other people's articles (Box 64, Folder 23)
    - Arms and Arms Control (Box 64, Folder 24)
    - Test Ban: Politics (national) (Box 64, Folder 25)
    - Test Ban: Social Responsibility (Box 64, Folder 26)
    - Test Ban: Seismic Research Problems (Box 64, Folder 27)
    - Radio Broadcast on Russian Tests (1961) (Box 65, Folder 25)
    - Article by George Lamb on Underground Explosions, with letter (Box 65, Folder 27)
    - Miscellany related to Arms Control and Disarmament Agency (Box 67, Folder 1-2)
    - Draft of Section E "Discussion:" High altitude Detection (Box 68, Folder 33)
    - Geneva Conference - Discontinuance of Nuclear Weapons Tests (1958) (Box 68, Folder 47)
    - Geneva Test Conference (Box 68, Folder 48)
    - Negotiations on a Nuclear Test Ban (Box 68, Folder 66)
    - Summary of HAB Lectures and Testimony (1960) (Box 68, Folder 73)
    - Test Ban (1985-87) (Box 77, Folder 30-31)
    - Test Ban (Box 82, Folder 11)
    - Test Ban, General (1983-85) (Box 82, Folder 13)
    - Test Ban, Seismic Detection (Box 82, Folder 14)
    - Test Ban, Livermore (1983-86) (Box 82, Folder 15)
    - Test Ban, Proposal with Bacher and Long (Box 82, Folder 16)
    - Test Ban, Mexico Parliamentarians (Box 82, Folder 17)
    - Test Ban, Correspondence (1978) (Box 82, Folder 18)
    - University of California weapons testing (1987) (Box 82, Folder 42-43)
    - Livermore's X-ray Laser Debate, Woodruff (1988) (Box 82, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence on Nuclear Weapons Laboratories (1983) (Box 82, Folder 45)
    - Trinity Test 40 Year Anniversary - July 16, 1985 (Box 93, Folder 47)
    - Copenhagen Conference (1985) (Box 93, Folder 48)
  - Nuclear Winter
    - Sagan on Nuclear Winter (Box 82, Folder 25)
    - Nuclear Winter, Los Alamos work on it (1983-86) (Box 82, Folder 26)
    - Sagan, Conference "World After Nuclear War" (1983-84) (Box 82, Folder 27)
    - Nuclear Winter (Box 82, Folder 28)
    - Nuclear Winter, Biological and Miscellaneous (1983-84) (Box 82, Folder 29)
  - Strategic Defense Initiative (SDI, "Star Wars")
    - Articles by our friends (Box 80, Folder 17)
    - Letters and articles against SDI (Box 80, Folder 18)
    - Warnke-Hoopes, Longstreth-Pike (Box 80, Folder 19)
    - Ove Nathan, answered by Drell and York (Box 80, Folder 20)
    - Government Testimony (1984) (Box 80, Folder 21)
    - Field and Spergel, pledge not to accept support (Box 80, Folder 23)
    - Newspaper clips, both for and against (Box 80, Folder 24)
    - Bethe articles (Box 80, Folder 25)
    - Carter, Garwin, May 1986 (Box 80, Folder 26)
    - Betty Lal (Box 80, Folder 27)
    - Study by General Kent (Box 80, Folder 28)
    - Report to Senators Proxmire and Johnston (Box 80, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous articles (Box 80, Folder 30)
    - Eastport Study (re: Organization of computers) (Box 80, Folder 31)
    - Keyworth, Major Worden (Box 80, Folder 32)
    - X-ray Laser (Bethe's analysis) (Box 80, Folder 33)
    - Article in Aviation Week, etc. (Box 80, Folder 34)
    - Press Conference, etc., Washington, Oct. 29 1984, Related to Mondale campaign (Box 80, Folder 35)
    - Australia TV, January 1988 (Box 80, Folder 36)
    - U.S. Congress Office of Technology Assessment report, notes on Ed Gerry (Box 80, Folder 37)
    - Ash Carter, Bundy, Computing (Box 80, Folder 38)
    - SIPRI Symposium: "Outer Space - Can Militarism be Checked?" papers by Nahin, Kerr, Slocombe (Box 80, Folder 39)
    - "Star Wars" Slides (Box 80, Folder 40)
    - "Star Wars" in the media (Box 80, Folder 41)
    - Analysis for NATO by R. Banks, UK (Box 80, Folder 42)
    - Al Weinberg (Box 80, Folder 43)
    - Fusion Energy Foundation (Box 80, Folder 44)
    - Teller-Bethe Debate, Technology Review (Box 80, Folder 45)
    - Abrahamson-Sagan Debate (Box 80, Folder 46)
    - "Our Opponents" (Box 80, Folder 47)
    - Arguments, International Appeal, other supporters (Box 80, Folder 48)
    - "Star Wars" speech prepared for Moynihan (with Garwin) (Box 80, Folder 49)
    - "Interactive Discrimination Approaches," by E. Raiten and K. Tsipis (1986) (Box 80, Folder 50)
    - Reactions to Reagan's announcement of SDI (Box 80, Folder 51)
    - Soviet Scientists for Peace (Box 80, Folder 52-53)
    - "Physics of a Ballistic Missile Defense," by C. L. Grabbe, Iowa (1986) (Box 80, Folder 54)
    - Satellite Constellations - articles by Garwin, Petschek (Box 80, Folder 55)
    - Jonathan Dean, Confidential Memoranda (Box 80, Folder 56)
    - Bethe Publications Against SDI (Box 80, Folder 57)
    - Star Wars: Livermore Controversy (1987-88) (Box 82, Folder 30)
    - Garwin, SWARMJET (Box 82, Folder 31)
    - Laser Focus (1984) (Box 87, Folder 46)
    - Garwin - Assessments of S.D.I. (1981-86) (Box 93, Folder 27)
    - Union of Concerned Scientists (1982-85) (Box 93, Folder 29)
    - Star Wars - Soviet Report (Box 93, Folder 30)
    - Fast-burn Boosters - Garwin (1983-86) (Box 93, Folder 31)
    - Star Wars - Union of Concerned Scientists (UCS) (1984) (Box 93, Folder 34)
    - Star Wars - UCS - Garwin (1984) (Box 93, Folder 35)
    - Star Wars - Comments on UCS (1984-85) (Box 93, Folder 36)
    - Star Wars - Commentary (1984-85) (Box 93, Folder 37)
    - Star Wars - Wall Street Journal (1984-85) (Box 93, Folder 38)
    - Star Wars - Jastrow (1984-85) (Box 93, Folder 39)
    - SDI Newspaper Articles (1984-86) (Box 93, Folder 42)
    - Star Wars - Wall Street Journal, Commentary - Fossedal (1984-87) (Box 93, Folder 44)
    - Star Wars - other critics (1985) (Box 93, Folder 50)
    - Star Wars - Kampelman and others (1985) (Box 93, Folder 51)
    - Livermore: Garwin-Drell Calculations (1985) (Box 93, Folder 52)
    - Livermore: Yonas letter (1985) (Box 93, Folder 53)
    - Livermore: Teller (1985-86) (Box 93, Folder 54)
    - Star Wars: Quotes, articles (1985-87) (Box 93, Folder 55-56)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Doppler Effect (Box 65, Folder 29)
    - Gulf General Atomic (Box 67, Folder 25)
    - Atomic Weapons, etc. (Box 67, Folder 33)
    - Los Alamos: Notes (Box 67, Folder 60)
    - J. Robert Oppenheimer (Box 68, Folder 20)
    - White House Releases (Box 68, Folder 43)
    - Detroit Edison Company - Miscellaneous (1955-56) (Box 68, Folder 44-46)
    - Testimony to Senate Foreign Relations committee (Box 68, Folder 57-58)
    - Meson Factories (Box 68, Folder 60-61)
    - PUGWASH Meeting in Moscow (Box 68, Folder 62)
    - History of the Manhattan Project (Box 69, Folder 43)
    - J. R. Oppenheimer Case (Box 72, Folder 2-5)
    - Scientists for Humphrey (1968) (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Oppenheimer Case (1954) (Box 77, Folder 7-9)
    - Prominent Physicists: Bohr, Oppenheimer, Teller (Box 82, Folder 33)
    - Bohr, 100th Anniversary (Box 82, Folder 34)
    - Disarmament: Economic Conversion to Peacetime Production (1988) (Box 82, Folder 47)
    - Los Alamos Science (1983) (Box 87, Folder 33)
    - Multiple Scattering (ca. 1950) (Box 93, Folder 13)
    - MX (1952, 1982) (Box 93, Folder 14)
    - Livermore notes (1975) (Box 93, Folder 18)
    - Free Electron Laser - C. S. Chang (1978-79) (Box 93, Folder 20-23)
    - Farm Hall Conversations, 1945 (1992) (Box 95, Folder 24)
    - Los Alamos literature related to H bomb (1949) (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Los Alamos Reports (1954-92) (Box 96, Folder 2-3)
    - Annual Summary Reports on the Theoretical Physics Group (1963-69) (Box 96, Folder 6)
    - Annual Summary Reports on the Theoretical Physics Group (1969-74) (Box 96, Folder 18)
    - Black Hole (1991) (Box 97, Folder 22)
    - Kuwait Fires (1991) (Box 97, Folder 25)
    - Weapons History (Box 97, Folder 34)
- Series V. Correspondence
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence related to AEC (1946-47) (Box 65, Folder 21-22)
    - Addresses and open letter to J. F. Kennedy (Box 65, Folder 35)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 65, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence related to Dr. R. Citron (Box 65, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence with GE (Box 65, Folder 39)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence and paper (Box 65, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence related to disarmament (Box 65, Folder 41)
    - Paper on Fermi and correspondence related to Oak Ridge Laboratory (Box 65, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence related to Linus Pauling (Box 65, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence with Dr. B. Rossi and Governor N. Rockefeller (Box 65, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence related to Paul Simon (Box 65, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence related to New York Times Letter to the Editor (Box 65, Folder 46)
    - Correspondence with D. Northrup, Air Force (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - Memoranda (Box 67, Folder 45)
    - Miscellaneous regarding Oppenheimer article (Box 67, Folder 65)
    - Gredda re: Oppenheimer (Box 68, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence on shock waves (1941) (Box 69, Folder 13-14)
    - Correspondence and Fan mail (1938-53) (Box 69, Folder 16-17)
    - Correspondence related to trip (1951) (Box 69, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence on trips (1948-51) (Box 69, Folder 19-20)
    - Correspondence related to book Mesons and Fields by Bethe and de Hoffmann (1953-54) (Box 69, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence related to article in Saturday Evening Post (1962) (Box 69, Folder 22-23)
    - Correspondence/Calculations/Graphs on Segré Article (1971) (Box 69, Folder 30-31)
    - Letter to Fermi - Grades (1936-37) (Box 69, Folder 47)
    - Requests for Manuscripts (1946-48) (Box 76, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence on Books Published (1946-53) (Box 76, Folder 23)
    - Political Letters (1950) (Box 77, Folder 1-3)
    - Political Letters, etc. (1950) (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence and Reprints (1980) (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence - Burrows, Cooperstein (ca. 1983) (Box 78, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence - Alphabetical
    - A (Box 69, Folder 32-33)
    - A (1982-87) (Box 87, Folder 22)
    - A (1985-88) (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - American Physical Society (to 1955) (Box 69, Folder 34-38)
    - American Physical Society (Box 69, Folder 39-41)
    - American Physical Society (1951-52) (Box 69, Folder 48)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 69, Folder 42)
    - American Journal of Physics: McConnell (ESP) (Box 69, Folder 49)
    - Argonne National Library (Box 69, Folder 50)
    - AEC (Atomic Energy Committee; a.k.a. Committee on Atomic Energy) (Box 69, Folder 51-54)
    - Atomic Scientists of Chicago (Box 69, Folder 55)
    - B (Box 67, Folder 34)
    - B (Box 67, Folder 40)
    - B (Box 69, Folder 56-60)
    - B (Box 70, Folder 1-4)
    - B (1982-90) (Box 87, Folder 23)
    - B (1984-86) (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Bacher, R. F. (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Brookhaven National Laboratory (Box 70, Folder 6-8)
    - Brookhaven National Laboratory (1946-48) (Box 82, Folder 35)
    - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists (Box 70, Folder 9-10)
    - C (Box 67, Folder 41)
    - C (Box 70, Folder 11-15)